# JUSTIN VELANDER HOLT

justin@onthecodeagain.com | +1-312-568-6632 | Chicago, IL

onthecodeagain.com | linkedin.com/in/velander | github.com/justinvholt

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Junior web developer on the cusp of a long-awaited career launch. I've spent three years studying code and building apps while living on the road. 170,000 miles and many git pushes later I am ready to join a team and establish a solid reputation as a dependable, diligent and accomplished full stack developer.

US Citizen · Open to Relocation · Available to Start Immediately

### **SKILLS**

- Ruby
- Javascript
- Ruby on RailsHTML
- CSS

- SQL
- Java
- Python
- ReactJSHeroku
- ¡Query

- Bootstrap
- Linux
- Github

### **EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer (Freelance) | OnTheCodeAgain.com

12/2017 - Present

Freelance/open-source web development. Notable projects include:

- On the Code Again (2019) Personal web site portfolio; built with Ruby, Javascript, ¡Query and Ruby on Rails.
- Chronos (2018) Automated laytime management system to assist with processing late fees for cargo shipping; built with Ruby, Javascript, ¡Query and Ruby on Rails. Tasked with allowing users to edit and save information within the view page for easier navigation. Later oversaw front-end continuity and button design.
- dopcast (2018-2019) Comprehensive podcast search engine; built with Ruby, Javascript and Ruby on Rails. Currently assisting founder with second iteration of app that will allow for faster loading time and easier navigation.
- BFN Networks (2000-2014) Podcasting network site. Three versions of site have been built and maintained using HTML, CSS, XML, Wordpress and Bootstrap.

### Auditor (Contract) | Phase 1 Medical Trials

03/2016 - 06/2019

 Collating and organizing paperwork for individual Phase I medical trials for facilities nationwide, ensuring accuracy and compliance per pharmaceutical drug sponsors' guidelines

## **EDUCATION**

Le Wagon – Rio de Janeiro, BR

2018

**Certification:** Web Development

- 9-week intensive coding boot camp specializing in full stack development Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, Javascript, iQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Linux, Github and Heroku
- Team lead and demo presenter for capstone project: <a href="https://youtu.be/W0UOC5IJ4wo?t=400">https://youtu.be/W0UOC5IJ4wo?t=400</a>

University of Illinois at Chicago - Chicago, IL, USA

2003

**Bachelor of Arts:** Creative Writing